It was more than three years since Lewis Nixon and I...
我和路易士·尼克森决定加入伞兵部队
...decided to join the paratroops.
至今已经三年多
And more than a year since we'd first gone to war...
距离我们首次参战也一年多了
...not knowing what would happen to us.
当时不知道我们会发生什么事
How long we'd be fighting where we'd end up.
要打多久 在哪里结束
I certainly didn't expect to find myself in a place like this.
我当然没料到自己会出现在这样的地方
I thought it might be you.
我猜是你
'Morning.
早安
I heard reports about a red-headed Eskimo.
我听到报导说有个红发的爱斯基摩人在此出没
Thought I'd check it out.
我就想过来看个究竟
Come to join me for a morning swim?
你要跟我一起晨泳吗?
Yeah. You know me so well.
是哦 你太了解我了
Here, it's from Zielinski.
拿去 这是泽林斯基给你的
Oh, great.
太好了
What is that?
那是什么?
Ran into the regimental photographer.
我遇到了团部的摄影师
Said he had all these photographs of the 506th...
他说他有506团的照片
...going all the way back to Toccoa.
从塔可亚基地到现在
I traded them for a couple of Lugers.
我用好几把鲁格枪换来的
That's a bargain.
那可真划算
What do you think you'll do after this?
这里结束后你想做什么?
Get some breakfast.
弄个早餐吃
No, after, after.
不是 再之后呢?
Well, it's funny you should mention it...
真有趣 你也提到这
...'cause I had a meeting with Colonel Sink.
因为我跟辛克上校开过会
Really?
真的?
Yeah.
对
Yeah, he and I discussed the possibility of staying.
讨论到留下来的可能性
In the Army?
留在陆军?
Yeah.
对
Yeah, as a career.
当做事业
What'd you say?
你怎么说?
I said I'd think about it.
我说我会考虑
What do you think about New Jersey?
你觉得纽泽西州如何?
New Jersey?
纽泽西?
There's a company in Nixon, New Jersey.
在纽泽西的尼克森有间公司
It's called "Nixon Nitration Works".
叫做尼克森化肥产品
Sounds picturesque.
听来挺动人的
Yeah, well, oddly enough I know the owners.
我刚好认识老板
Probably gonna expect me to make something of myself.
他可能希望我接手事业
I thought maybe I'd drag you with me.
我想也许我该拉你进来
Are you offering me a job?
你是在提供我工作机会吗?
We'll see how you do in your interview...
得看你在面试时的表现
...but, you know, a man of your qualifications...
可是有像你这样的历炼
...I think we can probably scrape something up. Commensurate with your current salary level.
我想我可以尽量找个和你现在薪水差不多的职位
Yeah, I'll think about it.
好 我会考虑看看
I really appreciate it.
我真的很感激
Yeah, just think about it.
你考虑看看
Yeah.
好的
Job offers. Hard to fathom.
工作机会 难以想象
And the war wasn't even over.
战争都还没有结束
I was still getting used to hot showers and morning swims.
我还在慢慢适应有热水澡跟晨泳的日子
We'd entered Bavaria in early May...
我们在五月初进入巴伐利亚
...with the hopes of capturing Berchtesgaden.
希望能够攻下贝希特斯加登
This famous town, high in the Alps...
这个著名的城镇高居于阿尔卑斯山区
...was the Nazi party's symbolic home...
是纳粹党的精神大本营
...and all the heads of the Third Reich had houses there.
而且第三帝国的首领们在此都有住所
Although Hitler was dead, he had apparently ordered the SS to make it their last stand...
虽然希特勒已死 他却命令武装党卫军将此处
...from which to mount a guerrilla resistance against the Allied advance.
当成对抗盟军进攻的最后守卫据点
The first step was blocking the roads.
第一步就是封锁道路
When are we expecting the engineers to arrive?
工兵应该何时出现?
Half an hour ago.
半个小时前
We're stuck here until they do, Nix.
他们来之前我们只能困在这里
Well, if you're the SS...
如果你是党卫军...
...you're not gonna let us waltz into Hitler's house.
也不会让我们跳着华尔兹进入希特勒的房子
Probably throw a few rocks at us yourself.
你也会朝我们丢石头
If you want someone to find a way up that mountain...
如果你要找人绕道攻上山头
...Easy Company is ready.
Ｅ连已准备好也很愿意去
Duly noted.
我了解
I already recommended you to Colonel Sink.
我也向辛克上校这样建议了
Let's go find out where Hitler lived.
咱们去找出希特勒的巢穴吧
Ron, we're not sure what's up there.
朗 我们不确定上面有什么
The Colonel doesn't want us taking any unnecessary risks.
上校不希望我们冒不必要的险
So, the French are gonna beat us to the Eagle's Nest.
那就让法国人先一步攻下鹰巢?
Gents, I just had a conversation with General Leclerc.
各位 我刚和勒克莱尔将军通话
He said he was first into Paris...
他说他是第一位进入巴黎的将领
...and by God he wanted to be first into Berchtesgaden.
也想第一个进入贝希特斯加登
Told him I understood his point.
我说我明白他的意恩
You fire up 2nd battalion and outflank that French son of a bitch.
你现在动员第二营抢在法国混蛋的前面
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
I want Easy Company in the lead.
我要Ｅ连做先头部队
Have the men assemble on the highway.
叫弟兄们在下面高速公路上集合
Yes, sir.
是 长官
Eerie. Not even any natives.
诡异 没看到半个居民
That's 'cause this is the one town you can't deny being a true Nazi.
因为没人能否认这是个纯纳粹的城镇
What do you mean?
你是什么意思?
Well, you have to be to live here.
住在这里你就知道了
Need to find some place we can put the Colonel.
我们得帮上校找个落脚的地方
How about right there?
那里如何?
No, no.
别拿走
Kitty would love this.
凯蒂一定会爱死这个
How many brides get a wedding present from Hitler?
有多少新娘能够拿到希特勒送的结婚贺札?
You wanna take half?
你要不要拿一半走?
I can't carry all this.
我没办法全部带走
You know, whoever comes in here after us...
你知道不管谁在我们之后进来
...is gonna take whatever isn't nailed down.
都会把所有没钉死的全搬走
Well...
嗯
...wouldn't want that to happen.
可不希望他们有这机会
Nice.
好东西
Don't even think about it.
你想都别想
Major Winters. Sir.
温特斯少校 长官!
More.
摩尔
Permission to climb the mountain, sir?
请求登山许可 长官
Eagle's Nest?
进攻鹰巢
What is this?
这是什么?
Wait one minute.
等一下
Harry, have F Company put a double guard on the hotel. Set up roadblocks on the west side of town.
哈利 叫Ｆ连加强守护旅馆 在城西设置路障
I want battalion HQ, seal off the north side and prepare for prisoners.
我要在此设置营总部 将北边封锁准备接收战俘
Sergeant Grant.
葛兰特中士
And, Harry, nobody gets hurt, not now.
还有 哈利 不要有人受伤 现在不能
And Easy?
那Ｅ连呢?
Easy will head up the mountain through the Obersalzburg...
Ｅ连由奥柏萨尔斯堡上山
...and take the Eagle's Nest.
攻下鹰巢
Hi-ho, Silver!
冲啊 骏马!
The Eagle's Nest was a surprise birthday present for Hitler...
老鹰之巢是用纳粹的钱帮希特勒盖的...
...built with Nazi party money.
一个惊喜生日札物
A mountaintop stone retreat 8,000 feet up...
是一座标高八千英尺的石材碉堡
...accessible by a gold-plated elevator.
由一座镀金的电梯进出
It was one of the crown jewels of his empire...
这是他帝国皇冠上的一颗宝石
...and the man was afraid of heights.
可是他却有畏高症
Here's to him.
这是敬他的
No, goddamn it, listen.
不是 可恶 听着
Hitler, Hitler, no.
希特勒 不 不...
Hitler, Himmler, Goering, Goebbels.
- 希姆莱、戈培尔... - 有没有人说你不会讲笑话
and the pope walk into a bar...
教宗走进一间酒吧
- Because he drinks too much... - That's how it starts.
- 因为他喝了太多... - 事情就是这么发生的
Hey, Adolf. Love your Eagle's Nest.
阿道夫! 我喜欢你的鹰巢
I hope you don't mind. We made ourselves at home.
我希望你不介意 我们已经把它当做自己家
Love what you've done with it.
我喜欢你这里的布置
Hey, hey, have a drink. Come on.
来一杯吧 快点
Just so as we can say we saw you do it.
我们才能说终于看到你喝酒了
Listen up.
注意听好
From Corps, just came in.
刚从军团来的命令
Effective immediately.
即刻生效
All troops stand fast on present positions.
所有的部队暂时在原地驻守
Standing fast.
原地驻守?
Wanna hear it?
你们要听吗?
Ready for it, listen up. The German army surrendered.
准备好了吗 听好 德军投降了!
I got a present for you, come on.
我有个礼物给你 来吧!
- Is it? - yeah.
- 就这样吗? - 没错
- What is this place? - Hermann Goering's house.
- 这是什么地方? - 赫曼戈林的房子
We discovered it yesterday. Had it on double guard ever since.
昨天发现后便派双哨看守
I can vouch for that.
这个我可以见证 长官
Oh, anxious to get off duty, O'Keefe?
等不及要下哨了吗 欧基夫?
No, there's just so much to see and do, sir.
没有 只是有太多要看要做的事 长官
Ten thousand bottles of the world's finest liquor...
上万瓶世界上最好的烈酒
...wine, and champagne helped Easy Company mark the day the war in Europe came to an end.
葡萄酒及香槟为Ｅ连记下了欧战结束的那一天
It's all yours.
全都是你的了
Take what you want and have each company take a truckload.
想拿多少就拿多少 然后叫每连载一卡车走
We're going to Austria in the morning. Don't feel obliged to leave stuff for whoever comes next.
我们明早就要前住奥地利 不用留给后面的人
Austria, sir?
奥地利吗 长官
Happy V.E. Day.
"ＶＥ"日快乐
Yeah.
对
V.E. day?
"ＶＥ"日?
Victory in Europe.
欧战胜利日
Happy V.E. Day.
欧战胜利日快乐
Instead of an aggressive combat unit...
不像一支攻击性的战斗部队
...we became an occupation force...
我们反倒成了占领军
...and no one wanted to leave Berchtesgaden...
没有人想离开贝希特加登
...until they saw Austria.
直到我们看到了奥地利
So, you reckon they'll make us run up those or ski down them?
你想上级会要我们爬上山还是滑雪下来?
Hey, how are you?
你好
Need a hand there?
需要帮忙吗?
He loves you!
他爱你
Hey, lady, how are you?
小姐 你好吗?
I think the war is over.
战争结束了
We'll be comfortable here.
我们在这儿会很舒服的
I wonder what will happen to us...
我在想当战争终于结束时
...to people like you and me when there are finally no more wars to occupy us.
像你我这样的人 命运将会是如何?
Have all your men collect the weapons...
叫你的部队缴械
...deposit them at the church, at the school, and at the airfield.
然后把它放在教堂 学校跟机场
Very well.
很好
Please accept this as my formal surrender, Major.
请你收下这个当做是我正式的投降 少校
It is better than to lay it on the desk of a clerk.
这样会比放在一个文书兵的桌上来的好
You may keep your sidearm, Colonel.
你可以留着你的手枪 上校
Heroic dead of a combined army and marine force mark the grim battlefield of Okinawa...
陆军及海军陆战队弟兄的英勇牺牲 为正在进行中的
...where one of the worst battles of the war is being fought.
战史上最血腥战斗之一的冲绳岛之役留下注脚
Thousands of Yanks have been wounded or sacrificed their lives...
有上千名美国人受伤 并且已经有数千名
...to drive a fanatical foe from this base.
为了设法将疯狂的敌人赶出他们的巢穴而阵亡
Along the Jap's southern defense line...
延着日军南边的防线
...the Yanks progress slowly facing one of the fiercest artillery barrages of the war.
美军遭遇到空前猛烈的炮击而进度缓慢
Each small advance is gained by sheer grit...
每一小步进展都是藉由英勇对抗
...in the face of withering fire from a suicidal enemy...
强做困兽之斗的敌军自杀攻击
...being slowly hammered back into the hills.
并将其慢慢逐回山头而取得
The going is brutal and our casualties are high...
战事惨烈的进行着 而我们的伤亡惨重
...but Okinawa is the next big step towards victory over Japan.
可是冲绳是战胜日本的一大步
A victory that can only be won by work...
这个胜利唯有藉着努力工作
...war bonds, and heroic sacrifice.
战争债券以及英勇的牺性
- So, when are we going? - We don't have a date yet.
- 我们什么时候要去? - 还没有确定日期
Are we to tell the men right away?
要现在跟弟兄们说吗?
Some of them will have enough points to go home instead.
有些人反而会拿到足够点数而退伍
Not many if their only medal's a Purple Heart.
不会很多 如果只得过紫心勋章的话
I think most of us here will have enough.
我想我们几个都会有足够的点数
And each of us will have to decide what to do.
我们每个人将要决定下一步要做什么
I don't know how long we're waiting here for orders...
我不知还要在此待命多久
...but I want those veterans who are staying...
可是我要决定留下的老兵...
...and all new replacements, ready to fight.
及所有新兵随时备战
That means rifle ranges.
这表示要做射击训练
That means daily close order drills. That means troop reviews...
紧急受命演习与部队检讨
...but, above all, it means physical training.
可是最重要的是体能训练
Get your NCOs on it.
叫你的士官们去执行
They're gonna love you.
他们会爱死你的
What are you crouching down for, Perco?
你蹲下来干什么 派康提?
Think the deer's gonna shoot back?
你以为鹿会向你开几枪吗?
Leave me alone.
你少管我
How about you all just shut up...
你们何不都闭嘴
...and let Shifty kill us some dinner?
让西福弟帮我们射只晚餐来吃?
What's the matter, Bull?
怎么了 大牛?
You tired of eating dried up spuds three times a day?
你吃腻三餐的干马铃薯吗?
Hey, you know what, I got an idea. Why don't we just shoot Bull here...
我想到个主意 干脆我们把大牛给杀了
...and feed the company for a week?
来喂连上一个星期
Oh, goddamn it, Shifty.
可恶 西福弟
You let him get away. Army ought to be glad to be rid of you.
你让它跑了 陆军一定很庆幸你要退伍了
I wish, you know. It seems they want me to stay around awhile.
希望是这样 可是看来他们还要我多留一阵
- Are you serious? - How many points you need?
- 你没开玩笑吧? - 你还需要几点?
Fifteen.
15点
Fifteen! Jesus Christ, I thought I had it bad.
15点? 天啊 我还以为我已经够多点了
No Purple Hearts, never was injured.
我没得过紫心勋章 也没受过伤
Company! Platoon! Attention!
全连各排注意! 立正!
Right shoulder. Arm!
上右肩~托枪!
Order. Arms!
枪~放下!
At ease.
稍息
General Taylor is aware that many veterans...
泰勒将军知道有很多老兵
...including Normandy veterans...
包括参与诺曼底空降的老兵
...still do not have the 85 points required to be discharged.
还没有累积到足够退伍的85分点数
On this the anniversary of D-day...
在今天这个D日纪念日
...he has authorized a lottery to send...
他给大家一次抽奖机会
...one man home in each company...
每连有一位兄弟能退伍返乡
...effective immediately.
即刻生效
For Easy Company, the winner is...
Ｅ连的中奖者
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
拜托
Serial number 13066266.
兵籍号码13066266
Sergeant Darrell C. Powers.
戴若包尔斯中士
Shifty
西福弟
That's how it's done, Shifty.
这是你应得的 西福弟
Congratulations, Shifty.
恭喜了 西福弟
Sergeant Grant will see to it that 2nd Platoon takes over at the crossroads checkpoint...
葛兰特中士负责带第二排去路口检查哨换防
...beginning tonight at 2200 hours.
从今晚10点开始
- So much for our anniversary. - No shit.
- 周年庆就此结束了 - 没错
General Taylor has also announced that the 101st Airborne Division...
泰勒将军也同时宣布101空降师
...will definitely be redeployed to the Pacific.
绝对会被重新布置在太平洋
So, beginning tomorrow, at 0600 hours...
所以从明早6点开始
...we will begin training to go to war.
我们要开始作战训练
Come in.
进来
I don't mean to interrupt you, sir.
我无意来打扰你 长官
I just wanted to say goodbye.
我只是想来...道别
You know, you was...
你知道 你是...
You was...
你是...
Well...
嗯...
It's been a long time.
我跟着您好久了
You got everything you need?
东西都带齐了吗?
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
I gathered up my loot. Pistols mainly.
我把战利品收好了 大部分是手枪
Paperwork's all done. I even got my back pay in my pocket.
表格都写好了 我甚至已经拿了退伍金
Back, back home in Virginia...
回到在维吉尼亚的家
Well...
嗯...
I just don't rightly know how I'm gonna explain all this.
我只是不知道该如何向别人解释这一切
You see, I've...
你知道
I've seen... I've seen...
我曾见过...我曾见过...
You're a hell of a fine soldier, Shifty.
你是一个非常杰出的军人 西福弟
There's nothing more to explain.
没有什么需要解释的
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你 长官
Two days later, Shifty Powers was on a truck headed for the rear and a boat home.
两天后 西福弟包尔斯坐上卡车 朝回家的船出发
Unfortunately the truck was hit head-on by a drunken corporal from another regiment.
不幸被一辆由别团一个酒醉的下士驾驶的车迎面撞上
Shifty had a broken pelvis...
西福弟骨盆碎裂
...a broken arm, and a bad concussion.
一只手骨折 并有严重的脑震荡
He survived, but spent the next few months in a series of hospitals.
虽然活了下来 可是得在医院多住几个月
I wish I could say that he was our only casualty in Austria.
我真希望我能说 他是我们在奥地利的唯一伤亡人员
I've made up my mind, Nix.
我已经决定了 尼克
I got the points, I'm going back to Kitty.
一旦我集满点数我就要回去找凯蒂
Harry, do you really think that Kitty hasn't run off with some 4-F by now?
哈利 你真的还认为 凯蒂没跟被退役的男人跑了
Son of a bitch. That's not even funny.
王八蛋 一点都不好笑
Harry, ignore him.
哈利 别理他
How am I supposed to tell her I had the chance to go home to her finally...
我怎么告诉她说 我本来终于有机会回家找她
...but decided not to, so I could go jump on Tokyo?
却为了想要空降东京而决定放弃?
All right, so don't tell her.
好 那就别告诉她
Besides, she's waited for you for three years, right?
反正她已经等了你三年了 对不对?
We'll be to Tokyo and back in two years, three tops.
我们去东京再回来差不多只要两年 最多三年
It'll probably be over before you even get there.
可能在你去之前就会结束了
The reality is you're gonna sit here in Austria for six months waiting to go...
事实上 你会在奥地利待上半年准备出发
...and I'm gonna be back in Wilkes-Barre making babies.
而我会回到我的温柔乡生小孩
- You didn't tell him? - No, I couldn't get him to shut up.
- 你还没告诉他? - 还没 我就是没办法让他闭嘴
What, tell me what?
什么? 告诉我什么?
Guts and Glory here applied for a transfer.
这位荣誉军人申请转调
What?
什么?
13th Airborne are heading out for the Pacific right away.
第13空降师马上要向太平洋战区出发
If I'm going, I wanna get it over with.
如果我要去 我在这里需要做个了结
Are you in on this too?
你也要去吗?
I can't let him go by himself. He doesn't know where it is.
我不能让他一个人去 他会找不到路的
You're leaving the men?
你要离开兄弟们?
They don't need me anymore.
他们不再需要我了
Wounded in Normandy?
在诺曼底受伤?
Yes, sir. In the leg. It was a minor flesh wound.
是 长官 在腿部 只是轻微的皮肉伤
Company E lost 24 men killed there.
Ｅ连在那里损失了24名兄弟
Yes, sir.
是 长官
Seventeen of those were in my company commander's plane. It went down on D-day.
其中17名是在我连连长搭乘的飞机上 他们在D日那天坠毁了
So, you were given command of the company on D-day?
所以你在D日那天受命指挥全连?
That's right.
是的
Fall back to your original positions!
退回你原来的据点
Everyone else maintain your pace of fire!
其他人保持火力
In Holland they bumped you to battalion XO.
在荷兰 他们...把你升去当副营长
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
Bastards took your company away.
混蛋们把你的连抢走了
I fired my last shots there.
我在那里开了我最后一枪
For the whole damn war?
在整个战争里?
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
You got through Bastogne without having to fire your weapon?
你未发一枪一弹经历了巴斯通之役?
That is correct, sir.
正确 长官
And you were on the line the whole time?
而你一直都在战线上?
Yes, sir.
是 长官
Can't imagine a tougher test for a leader...
无法想象对领导者有更严酷的考验
...having to sit through a siege like that under those conditions.
在那些状况下撑过围城之苦
We got through it.
我们熬过来了
Find some cover, find a foxhole!
找掩体 找散兵坑
Come on, take cover! Take cover!
快点 找掩体
Come on, find some cover!
快点 快找掩体
Why do you want a transfer?
你为什么要转调?
Sorry, sir?
对不起 长官?
I said, why do you want to leave your men?
我说你为何要离开你的兄弟?
It's not that, sir.
不是这样的 长官
It's just that if the war was still on in the Pacific...
我是想太平洋还有战事
...and I could do some good over there.
我还能够协助作战
Looking to have your own division someday?
你是不是想当上师长?
No, sir.
不是的 长官
Not going to make a career of the army?
你不想在陆军里发展?
No. Well, I don't know, sir.
不是 我不知道 长官
Because if you think you need more combat experience...
如果你是想获得更多的作战经验
...to get stars on your helmet...
来争取你头盔上的星星的话
...let me tell you something, son.
让我告诉你一件事 孩子
You've done enough.
你做的够多了
Thank you, sir. That's not my objective.
谢谢你 长官 那不是我的目的
Major, I took this meeting out of respect for your achievements and for the 101st.
少校 这次会面 我增加了对你和101师的尊敬
If they do go to the Pacific eventually you should be running one of the battalions.
如果他们最终会被派往太平洋 你应该指挥其中的一个营
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你 长官
And frankly, your men have earned the right to keep you around.
老实说 我认为你的兄弟有权利将你留下来
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你 长官
So, I would stay in Austria for the time being waiting for orders...
所以我暂时得留在奥地利待命
...and trying to watch over soldiers who had no enemy to fight.
想办法看好无敌可战的士兵们
Lieb, I fucking hate this.
李 我不喜欢这样
Oh, Jesus Christ, they fingered him.
拜托 他们已经指认他了
He was in the fucking room, Web.
他曾出现在营房里 韦伯
A Polack who was at the slave camps said this is where he lives, here.
在集中营的一个波兰人说那家伙就住在这里
- Which camp? - Whatever camp.
- 哪个集中营? - 管他是哪个
I'm under direct orders and I'm happy to follow it.
我是直接受命的 而且我乐于奉命行事
Is this a personal thing, Joe?
这是你的私事吗 乔?
What?
什么?
Is this personal to you?
这是你的私事吗?
No, it's a goddamn order.
不是 这是个命令
Does Major Winters know about this?
温特斯少校知道这件事吗?
Doesn't matter here.
这无关紧要了
Oh, the fuck it doesn't.
无关紧要个屁!
What if this guy's just a soldier?
如果这家伙只是个普通的士兵呢?
What if he's an officer with no ties to the SS?
如果他是个跟党卫军毫无瓜葛的军官呢?
If he's innocent? You know...
如果他根本是无辜的?
...what if he's a fucking Nazi commandant of a slave camp?
如果他是奴隶营里的指挥官?
Which one, which camp? You don't have any proof.
哪一个? 哪个集中营? 你没有任何证据
Were you at Landsberg?
你有去兰登斯堡吗?
You know I was.
你明知我有去
You think he's a soldier like you and me?
你以为他是和你我一样的士兵?
A fucking innocent German officer?
一个无辜的德国军官?
Where the hell have you been for the past three years?
你过去三年到哪里去了?
Wer sind Sie?
(德语)
What?
什么?
Shut up.
闭嘴
Was machen Sie?
(德语)
Nein, nein.
不是
Don't fucking lie to me.
不要骗我
Sie tauschen sich.
(德语)
See what you did to my fucking people?
你看看你对我同胞做了什么!
He's guilty.
他有罪
- Liebgott says so. - He probably is.
- 李高特说他有罪... - 那就是有罪了
Goddamn son of a bitch. Shoot him.
可恶的王八蛋 打他!
Shoot him!
开枪打他!
No.
不要
Officers don't run.
军官不该逃的
The war's over, anybody would run.
战争结束了 换做是谁都会逃
Summer in this Alpine paradise should have been a welcome relief...
在这山中仙境的夏日本该令人放松
...especially now that we were at peace with the Germans.
尤其是现在我们跟德国人和平相处之后
Everyone just wanted to go home.
每个人都只想回家
France. France was the best.
法国 法国最棒了!
Really?
真的吗?
Yeah, five years.
对! 五年了
I think I was in every country, but France was the best.
我想我每个国家都去过了 可是法国是最棒的
Italy would be second for me.
意大利会是我第二个选择
Russia is not desirable. Ukraine, it was okay.
俄罗斯不行 乌克兰还好
So, when do you get out?
你什么时候退伍?
The unit is discharged. We leave when my captain gets transferred.
部队已经解散了 等连长转调后就可以离开了
It is the end of my second war.
这是我第二个战争的结束
Jesus.
老天
I'm going home now to Mannheim.
我要回家了 在曼海姆
I'll take this one.
这辆车由我来
Passkarte, bitte.
(德语)
Okay.
好了
Hey, Webster.
嘿 韦伯斯特...
- My relief. - Don't salute the Germans.
- 我的替哨 - 不要向德军敬札
Come on. I sort of get a kick out of it.
别这样 我觉得蛮好玩的
Anyway, I got me a new enemy. The Japs.
不管怎样 我现在有新的敌人 日本鬼子!
75 points. How about you? I mean, you're a Toccoa guy, right?
75点 你呢? 你是塔可亚出身的 对吗?
- How many you got? - Wouldn't you like to know?
- 你有几点呢? - 你不会想要知道的
Discharged, huh?
退伍了是吗?
- Go ahead, take off, it's my turn. - Okay, see you back at the farm.
- 去吧 你走 该我站了 - 好 我们回头见
Eighty-one.
81点
What?
什么?
I have 81 points.
我有81点
Well, that's just not good enough.
看来还是不够
See about getting you a ride.
我看能不能帮你找个便车
Hey!
嘿!
Where are they going?
他们要去哪里?
Munich. Munchen, Munich.
慕尼黑
Wanna go to Munich?
你要去慕尼黑吗?
Mochten Sie nach Munchen gehen?
(德语)
Get in.
上车
Too bad.
真可惜
Turn the wheel!
方向盘
Oh, Jesus.
我的天
It's Private Janovec.
是二等兵杰诺维克
He was dead when they brought him in.
送他来时他已经断气了
75 points.
75点
- What? - He was 10 points short.
- 什么? - 他只差10点
The enemy had surrendered, but somehow men were still dying.
敌军已经投降了 可是阿兵哥们还是继续死亡
Young men, who wanted to be home with their families by now...
从诺曼底前服役至今的年轻士兵 虽然有着卓越的表现
...who'd served with distinction since before Normandy...
就算想在此时与家人团聚
...were stuck here because they didn't have the points.
却因点数不足而坐困在此
What they did have plenty of were weapons, alcohol, and too much time on their hands.
他们有的只是武器 酒精 还有手中太多的时间
When all of a sudden, from out of nowhere...
他拼命想挣脱他的伞带
...a guy jumps out of the hedgerow...
突然不知从哪儿冒出来一个家伙 跳出树丛
...onto this guy's chest.
冲出来压住他的胸膛
Shoves a trench knife up against his throat and screams, "Whose side are you on?"
将刀子抵住他的喉咙大喊"你是哪一边的? "
I don't get it.
我听不懂
It's D-day.
在D日那天
It's 2nd platoon's own Bill Guarnere. Old' Gonorrhea himself.
是第二排的比尔葛奈瑞 人称老淋病先生
Just landed in Normandy and wound up like I don't know what.
才刚降落在诺曼底就兴奋的跟什么一样
"Whose side are you on?" What a fucking character!
"你是哪一边的"? 真是个怪胎
What happened to him?
他后来怎么样了?
Got his leg blown off in Bastogne.
他的脚在巴斯通给炸断了
Wait here.
在这里等着
Are you okay, Mac, do you need some help?
你还好吗 朋友? 你需要帮忙吗?
They wouldn't give me any gas.
他们一点汽油都不给我
Krauts.
臭德仔
I tried to explain.
我试着解释
This fucking limey wouldn't listen.
这些臭德军就是不听
I think he was a Major.
我想他是个少校
Look, Private, we've got a problem here.
你听着 阿兵哥 我们这里出问题了
Do you have any gas?
你有汽油吗?
Why don't you give me your weapon?
把你的枪给我好吗
Well, I guess I'll just use his Jeep. I don't think he's gonna be needing it.
那我只好开他的吉普车 我想他是用不着了
Hold on a second there, all right?
你站在原地别走
Jesus.
老天
Sarge! Sergeant Grant!
中士! 葛兰特中士
Sarge!
中士
Jesus.
老天
What?
怎样?
He's not gonna make it.
他活不成了
You can't operate on him?
你不能动手术吗?
Not me.
我没办法
You'd need a brain surgeon.
你需要一位脑外科医生
And even if you had one, I don't think there's any hope.
就算你找到了 我也不认为有任何希望
Find the shooter. Alive. Come on, help me.
你去把凶手抓来 我要活口 过来帮我
What are you doing?
你要干什么?
We're gonna go find a brain surgeon.
我们去找脑外科医生
Hey, Lieb. He wants a noncom guarding each roadblock...
李 他要每个检查哨都要有位士官看管
...and two men watching every road out of town.
每条离开镇上的道路 要有至少两位士兵看守
Bull, Malark, you each pick a squad...
大牛 马拉其 你们每人挑选一班...
...and one witness on a house to house search.
及一位目击者做逐屋搜索
Can we shoot this bastard on sight?
可以当场格杀这个混蛋吗?
Try and take him alive.
尽量留下活口
Where's Grant now?
葛兰特现在在哪里?
They took him to a Kraut hospital...
他们送他去一间德军医院
...to see if they could drum up any good doctors.
看看能不能找到好医生
Open up.
开门
Come with me.
跟我来
Why?
为什么?
Get in the Jeep.
上吉普车
Where're we going?
我们要去哪里?
To the hospital, get in.
去医院 上车
If you're going to shoot me, shoot me.
你如果要对我开枪就动手
If you're not, put the gun away.
如果你不动手 就把枪拿开
Get in the Jeep, now.
快点 上吉普车
- What happened to him? - He was shot in the head.
- 他怎么了? - 他头部中弹
Half hour ago. Come on.
在半个小时前 快点!
If you want him to live, you'll help me.
如果你要他活下去 你就要帮我
First by putting that away.
首先把枪拿开
- Let's go. - Let me drive.
- 我们走 - 让我来开
We'll get there faster.
我们可以快一点到
Jesus. Again, what a hand.
老天 又是一手烂牌
I don't know who's taking a bigger beating, me or him.
不知道是谁比较惨 是我还是他?
Wanna play a different game?
玩别的游戏?
No.
不用
Same game, just shuffle them up good, huh?
就玩这种 你只要把牌洗好 好吗?
- You all right? - Yeah, I'm all right.
- 你还好吗? - 好 我很好
You wanna go in there and join in?
你要进去加入他们吗?
I should go in there and stop this.
我应该进去叫他们别再打了
Floyd, let's just play cards, all right?
佛洛依德 我们打牌就好 好吗?
Where is he?
人在哪里?
How's Grant?
葛兰特还好吗?
Is he okay?
他还好吗?
This him?
就是他吗?
That's him.
就是他
Replacement I Company.
Ｉ连的新兵
Where's the weapon?
武器在哪里?
What weapon?
什么武器?
When you talk to an officer, you say "sir."
当你跟军官说话时 你要说长官
Have the MPs take care of this piece of shit.
叫宪兵来处理这个人渣
- Grant's dead? - No.
- 葛兰特死了吗? - 没有
Kraut surgeon says he's gonna make it.
德国军医说他能活下来
Hey, tough guy, on your feet. Come on, move, move it.
硬汉 站起来 走了 快点 站起来
I'm guessing they were Hitler's photo albums, sir.
我猜那些是希特勒的相簿 长官
Sure had a lot of pictures of him in it.
里面有很多他的照片
You looked at them, but you didn't take them?
你看到那些相簿却一本也没拿?
That's right, sir.
是的 长官
I don't believe you.
我才不相信你
I'll be watching you.
我会盯着你
You're dismissed.
你可以走了
You'd better not be lying to me.
你最好别骗我
What?
什么事?
Sir, if it's not gonna put you in too much of a bind...
长官! 如果不会造成你太大困扰的话
...I'd like to resign as Company 1st Sergeant.
我想请辞连队军士长的职位
If I had my choice I miss being back amongst the men.
如果我能选择 我想念跟兄弟们一起的时光
I'd be happy to go to Staff Sergeant whichever platoon you wanna put me in.
我会很高兴担任幕僚士官 随便你要我去哪一排
Well, I guess you've earned your right to demote yourself.
我想你已经争取到自己降级的权利
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你 长官
You wanna take over Sergeant Grant's platoon?
你要不要带葛兰特中士那一班?
That would do fine, sir.
那很好 长官
All right then, report to Lieutenant Peacock.
那就好 向皮卡克少尉报到
Let me know if he gives you any trouble.
他要是找你麻烦就跟我说
Oh, sir, you make your decision yet?
长官 你做决定了吗?
Yeah, I did.
我决定了
So, what else is on your mind?
你心里还有什么打算?
I know Easy Company's gonna need a Commanding Officer post-war.
我知道Ｅ连在战后还需要一位连长
Somebody to hold their hand keep them from killing each other.
一个能够支持他们避免他们自相残杀的人
It better be somebody who knows what they're doing.
最好是个了解兄弟的人
Yep, I couldn't agree more.
对 我完全同意
It's absolutely irresponsible to leave them in the hands of the wrong person.
把他们交给不适任的人是绝对不负责任的
They're too much of a valuable resource to the military.
他们是军方无比珍贵的资源
So, you've decided to stay in the army?
你决定留在陆军了?
Yes, I'm gonna stay with the men.
是的 我要留下来陪他们
Well, I'm glad to hear it.
我很高兴听到你这么说
So, some of us would stay by choice...
所以有些人选择留下来
...but others were stuck if we couldn't find excuses to send them away.
可其他人却还困在这里 除非找到送走他们的理由
So, it's an airborne exhibition.
这是个跳伞表演
They have one of every Allied combat plane they've used in the war.
他们会出动每一种盟军参战的飞机
I mean, yes, sir.
我是说 是的 长官
You'll be like a technical adviser to make sure they get everything right.
你是技术顾问 确定他们不会出错
I understand, sir.
我了解了 长官
I'm sorry it's not a more hospitable location.
很抱歉 不是你最想去的地方
No, sir. Paris is just fine.
不会的 长官 巴黎...还可以啦
You know, if you need me to go...
如果你需要我去
- ...someone must be there. - Yeah, we do, we absolutely do.
- 总有人要去的 - 是的 我们需要 我们绝对需要
And your driver will drop you off at a hotel of your choice.
司机会送你到你挑选的旅馆
And I don't think we'll see you back here any time soon.
我想我们短时间内 不会在这里再看到你
I won't let you down, sir.
我不会让你失望的 长官
Carwood, yes.
卡伍德 对了...
I wanted to say...
我想说的是...
...as you probably know...
或许你已经知道
...when they give a man a battlefield commission make him an officer...
陆军在颁给一个人战场委任书升他当军官后
...they usually don't let him stay with the same company.
通常不会让他待在同一连
Yes, sir, I figured this was coming.
是的 长官 我已经料想到这一天的到来
Yeah, they're afraid the men won't show him the proper degree of respect as they would another officer.
对 是怕兄弟们不会给他对军官应有的尊敬
It's a good theory, sir.
这是个很好的理论 长官
It's an idiotic theory especially in your case.
这是个白痴的理论 特别是用在你的身上
Nevertheless, they've given me the choice as to where to re-assign you...
尽管如此 他们还是给了我重新指派你的选择
...and I thought battalion headquarters might be a good place.
而我想营指挥部应该是个好地方
I can think of few better, sir.
我想不出更好的地方了 长官
Good.
很好
Right now, down at the airfield there is a German general who is a little POed...
现在在机场那边有位德国将军
...about having to surrender to a private from South Philly.
对要向来自南费城的大兵贝比·赫夫朗投降有些迟疑
- Thinks it's beneath his stature. - Understandable, sir.
- 他觉得有失他的身份 - 这我能了解 长官
Yeah. I thought 2nd Lieutenant Carwood Lipton from West Virginia...
对! 我想来自西维吉尼亚的卡伍德·李普顿少尉...
...could soothe his ruffled feathers.
可以杀杀他的傲气
No problem, sir.
没问题 长官
Major, is this the type of job I can expect from now on?
少校 这是不是从现在开始...我可以期待的工作形态?
Yeah. Yeah.
对
When we're not sunning ourselves by the lake.
当我们不在湖边晒太阳的时候
Lieutenant.
少尉
With your permission, I would like to address my men briefly.
经由你的同意 我想跟兄弟们简短说些话
That'll be fine, General.
没问题 将军
Captain Sobel.
索柏上尉
- Major Winters. - Captain Sobel.
- 温特斯少校 - 索柏上尉
We salute the rank, not the man.
敬礼是看官阶 不是看人的
Manner...
(德语)
Liebgott?
李高特?
Men, it's been a long war, it's been a tough war.
这是个漫长的战争 也是一场艰苦的战争
lhr habt tapfer und stolz fur euer Vaterland gekampft.
(德语)
You have fought bravely, proudly for your country.
你们英勇...并骄傲的为祖国作战
You are a special group...
你们是不平凡的一群
...die ineinander einen Zusammenhalt gefunden habt...
(德语)
...who have found in one another a bond...
彼此紧密相连
...that exists only in combat.
这样的友谊只存在战斗中
Unter Kameraden...
(德语)
Among brothers...
在兄弟之间
...of shared foxholes.
共同使用散兵坑
Die sich in schrecklichen Momenten...
(德语)
Held each other in dire moments.
在最需要的时刻彼此扶持
Who've seen death and suffered together.
你们看过死亡 一起接受磨难
Ich bin stolz...
(德语)
I am proud to have served with each and every one of you.
我很骄傲能与你们每个人共同服役
You deserve long and happy lives of peace.
你们有权享受永远的快乐的和平生活
Towel, towel, towel, towel, towel.
毛巾
Thanks.
谢谢!
Take a look at these two kids.
看看这两个孩子
What the hell happened to them?
他们究竟发生什么事了?
New Jersey, huh?
纽泽西 是不是?
Yeah.
对
Think about it.
考虑看看
Yeah, I am.
有 我在考虑
You awake yet?
你睡醒了吗?
Awake?
睡醒?
Time to go to bed.
该上床睡觉了
Bad luck, Jimmy.
运气不好 吉米
Nice play.
守得好
Come on, we got one down.
来吧 一人出局了
Come on, Pee Wee, let's get Webster.
来吧 小不点 让我们解决韦伯斯特
Buck Compton came back to see the Company. To let us know that he was all right.
"巴克·康普顿"回到连上看大家 让大家知道他很好
He became a prosecutor in Los Angeles.
他后来成为洛杉矶的检察官
He convicted Sirhan Sirhan in the murder of Robert Kennedy...
他在罗伯特·肯里迪的谋杀案中 将凶手索罕定罪
...and was later appointed to the California Court of Appeals.
之后被指派任职于加州上诉法院
David Webster became a writer for The Saturday Evening Post and Wall Street Journal...
"大卫·韦伯斯特"成为周六邮报、华尔街日报的专栏作家
...and later wrote a book about sharks.
之后他写了本有关鲨鱼的书
In 1961, he went out on the ocean alone...
在1961年他独自出海之后
...and was never seen again.
就没有人再见过他了
Go, go, go!
跑
Johnny Martin would return to his job at the railroad...
"强尼·马丁"回到原先他在铁路公司的工作
...and then start his own construction company.
然后开设他自己的建筑公司
He splits his time between Arizona and a place in Montana.
在亚历桑纳及蒙大拿两地来回奔波
George Luz became a handyman in Providence, Rhode Island...
"乔治·鲁兹"在罗德岛州的普拉福登斯担任杂务工
...and as a testament to his character...
由于他极佳的人缘
...1600 people attended his funeral 1998.
1600人在1998年参加了他的丧札
Doc Roe died in Louisiana in 1998.
"罗医官"于1998年在路易斯安那逝世
He'd been a construction contractor.
他成为一位建筑承包商
Frank Perconte returned to Chicago and worked a postal route as a mailman.
"法兰克·派康提"回到芝加哥 在一间邮局担任邮递员
Joe Liebgott returned to San Francisco...
"乔·李高特"回到旧金山
...and drove his cab.
开他的出租车
Bull Randleman was one of the best soldiers I ever had.
"大牛·蓝道曼"是我带过最好的士兵之一
He went into the earth-moving business in Arkansas.
他在阿肯色州从事挖掘土方的事业
He's still there.
他还在那里
Alton More returned to Wyoming with a unique souvenir...
"奥顿·摩尔"带了一件特殊的纪念品回到怀俄明
...Hitler's personal photo albums.
就是希特勒的私人相簿
He was killed in a car accident in 1958.
他在1958年因车祸过世
Floyd Talbert, we all lost touch with in civilian life...
"佛洛依德·泰伯特"在解甲归田后 便与我们失去联络
...until he showed up at a reunion just before his death in 1981.
直到1981年 在他去世前的聚会中才再见到他
How we lived our lives after the war was as varied as each man.
我们战后的生活人人不同
Carwood Lipton became a glass-making executive...
"卡伍德·李普顿"成为玻璃工厂主管
...in charge of factories all over the world.
掌管的工厂遍及全球
He has a nice life in North Carolina.
在北卡罗荣纳过着美好的生活
Harry Welsh, he married Kitty Grogan...
"哈利·威尔旭" 他娶了"凯蒂·葛罗根"
...became an administrator for the Wilkes-Barre Pennsylvania school system.
成为威克司巴尔宾州分校的行政主管
Ronald Speirs stayed in the army served in Korea...
"隆纳德·史毕尔"留在陆军 参加了朝鲜战争
...and in 1958, returned to Germany as governor of Spandau prison.
并在1958年返回德国担任斯班朵监狱的典狱长
He retired a Lieutenant Colonel.
以中校阶级退伍
Get them round.
叫他们集合
Easy Company, school circle!
Ｅ连 成谈话队形!
For Easy Company, it was D-day plus 434.
对Ｅ连来说 这是D日后的第434天
A fast man would've had it, Perco.
脑筋快的人该想到了 派康提
Listen up, got some news.
注意听 有消息宣布
This morning President Truman received the unconditional surrender from the Japanese.
今天早上 杜鲁门总统接受了日本的无条件投降
War's over.
战争结束了
Regardless of points, medals, or wounds...
不管点数 勋章或是伤痕
...each man in the 101st Airborne would be going home.
每个101空降师兄弟都要回家了
Each of us would be forever connected by our shared experience.
我们每个人都会因为共同经历而永远相系
And each would have to rejoin the world as best he could.
每个人也必须尽力重新加入世界
War is over
战争结束了!
Lewis Nixon had some tough times after the war.
"路易士·尼克森"在战后不是很得意
He was divorced a couple of times.
离了几次婚
Then in 1956, he married a woman named Grace and everything came together for him.
1956年娶了"葛瑞丝" 从此一帆风顺
He spent the rest of his life with her, traveling the world.
他与她共度余生 四处旅游
My friend, Lew, died in 1995.
我的好友路易于1995年过世
I took up his job offer and was a personnel manager at the Nixon nitration works until I was called back...
我接受了他的工作 在尼克森化肥产品担任人事经理
...into service in 1950 to train officers and rangers...
直到1950年我被征召回部队 去训练军官及突击队员
...but I chose not to go to Korea. I'd had enough of war.
可我没有选择去朝鲜并以此为业 我已经历太多战争
I stayed around Hershey, Pennsylvania finally finding a little farm.
我在宾州贺胥待了下来 最后终于找到一处农场
A little peaceful corner of the world...
世界上平静的一个小角落
...where I still live today.
到现在我仍旧住在这里
And there is not a day that goes by that I do not think of the men I served with...
我没有一天不想 那些曾经与我一起服役...
...who never got to enjoy the world without war.
却未能有机会享受没有战争的日子的兄弟们
It's a very unusual feeling.
这是一个很奇特的感觉 (迪克·温特斯)
It's a very unusual happening and it's a very unusual bonding.
这是件很不平凡的事 它是个非比寻常的连结
We knew that we could depend on each other...
我们知道我们可以彼此依赖 (卡伍德·李普顿)
...and so, we were a close-knit group.
所以我们是很紧密的团体
Just brave, so brave it was unbelievable.
就是勇气 难以置信的勇敢 (马拉其 唐诺)
And I don't know anybody that I admire more than Bill Guarnere and Joe Toye.
我最崇拜比尔葛奈瑞还有乔托伊
And they were very, very special.
他们都很特别
I'm just one part of the big war, that's all.
我只是在大战里的一部分 如此而已
One little part.
一小部分 (比尔·加尼尔 中士)
And I'm proud to be a part of it.
而我很骄傲能参与其中
Sometimes it makes me cry.
有时候它会使我哭泣
The real men the real heroes are the fellows...
真正的男子汉 英雄们 (大兵 赫弗朗)
...that are still buried over there and those that came home to be buried.
是那些还埋在那里与殉国返乡被葬的人
It seemed like you thought that you could do...
感觉好象是你以为你能做任何事
...just about anything and after the war was over and you came back out.
当战争结束后你回到社会 (西福地·鲍尔斯)
Well, you lost a lot of that...
你丧失许多这种能力
...or at least I did.
至少我是如此
I lost all that confidence.
我丧失了原有的信心
We was hoping to stay alive, that's all, you know.
我只是想活下来 如此而已 (约翰·马丁)
Henry the Fifth was talking to his men.
亨利五世跟他的士兵们说话
He said, "From this day to the ending of the world...
他说从今天到世界末日
"...we in it shall be remembered.
我们永远会被记得
"We lucky few, we band of brothers.
我们幸运的少数 我们相系相依的兄弟
"For he who today sheds his blood with me shall be my brother."
谁今日与我共同浴血 他就是我的兄弟
Do you remember...
你还记得
...the letter that my granny wrote me?
我祖母写给我的信吗?
You do? Do you remember how I ended it?
你记得吗? 记得最后怎么结束的?
"I cherish the memories of a question...
我很珍惜这段记忆
"my grandson asked me the other day...
有天我孙子问我一个问题
"...when he said:
他问我:
"Grandpa, were you a hero in the war?"
"爷爷 你是大战中的英雄吗? "
Grandpa said, "No...
我回答: 不是
"...but I served in the company of heroes."
可是我与英雄们一起服役